Inventory of the W. P. Hammon papers
Hoover Institution Archives
W. P. Hammon papers
1915-1930
72007
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes, 7 envelopes (1.9 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, contracts, shipping lists, specifications for dredging equipment, annotated maps, and photographs, relating to mining operations in China, Siberia, Korea, Malaya, and Poland.
Hammon, W. P., 1854-1938.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American businessman; associated with Yuba Manufacturing Company, San Francisco.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, reports, contracts, shipping lists, specifications for dredging equipment, annotated maps, and photographs, relating to mining operations in China, Siberia, Korea, Malaya, and Poland.
Amtorg Trading Corporation.; Giesche Spolka Akcyjna Company.; Yuba Manufacturing Company of San Francisco.; Mines and mineral resources--China.; Mines and mineral resources--Korea.; Mines and mineral resources--Malaya.; Mines and mineral resources--Poland.; Mines and mineral resources--Soviet Union.; Tin mines and mining--Malaya.
- China and Siberia mining concessions for the Yuba manufacturing Company of San Francisco file (Box 1)
  - Corresponence and reports, 1921-22 (Box 1)
  - Maps (Box 1)
- Amtorg Trading Corporation contract with the Yuba Manufacturing Company of San Francisco file (Box 1)
  - Contracts and agreements, 1925-27 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1926-30 (Box 1)
  - Bills of lading, shipping lists, receipts (Box 1)
- Specifications for dredging equipment sold to the Chinese government and Japanese and Russian mining companies by the Yuba Manufacturing Company, 1912-1917 (Box 1)
- Tze-Liu-Tsing District (Eastern Part), mining reports, Korea (Box 2)
- Korea file (Box 2)
  - Preliminary Report, Anjo Property, Korea, Nelson Dickerman, July 5, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Preliminary Report on Placer Claims of the Chosen Kasan Co. in Chosen, Korea, Charles W. Gardner and H. R. Edwards, April 12, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Report of H. R. Edwards on Korean Project, May 4, 1921 (Box 2)
  - "Report on the Yung Hung Placers" (Korea), J.S. Bradford, 1920 (Box 2)
  - Blueprint of Asano Concessions Yeng Byen, Seichikori?, Korea (Box 2)
- Malaya file (Box 2)
  - Mechanical Report on Tin Dredging in Malaya, July 22, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Report on Tin Dredging in Malaya, March 1, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Mining Report on Tin Dredging in Malaya, July 22, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Resoiling and reclamation of rice lands, reports, memoranda, correspondence and drawings (Box 3)
- Poland, Giesche Spolka Akcyjna Company (Katowice, Poland), mining reports (Box 3)
- "The Mining Informer" (guide concerning wages and working hours of Coolies in China, compiled or written in 1920) (Box 3)
- "The World Economic Situation," by Herbert Hoover, 1919 (Box 3)
- Pro-Hoover campaign pamphlet, 1928 (Box 3)
- Photographs, 367 prints / 5 envelopes / 276 negatives / 2 envelopes (Photo file)
  - 55 photos of mining and land reclamation projects in Siberia, 1921-1922 (Envelope A)
  - 70 photos of scenes in daily life in Siberia, circa 1920 (Envelope B)
  - 500 photos of dredging equipment sent to the U.S.S.R. from the United States, circa 1947 (Envelope C-F)
  - 24 prints of American and European political leaders, 1921-1935 (Envelope G)